ALEX LEE

Human-Computer Interaction and Design



PROFILE

Senior student studying Cognitive Science with a Specialization in Human-Computer Interaction and a minor in Design at the University of California, San Diego. My interest in design is rooted in efficiency and simplicity. I believe that anything and everything can be improved through simple design. My goal is to combine my personal interests and academic background to help a tech-oriented company achieve their goals, increasing my knowledge of design along the way.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

- A goal-oriented, analytical and intuitive problem-solver
- Quick and adaptable in any given situation
- Studious and eager to absorb as much knowledge as possible
- Punctual, especially when it comes to meeting deadlines

EXPERIENCE

UX/UI Designer DJriver - UCSD

2017 - 2017

Created wireframes for a music app designed to ease the mental load of drivers. Our group of four went through the entire human-centered design process and created a final prototype posted on Invision. I conducted interviews, generated comparitive analyses, and developed the entire user flow of managing a playlist.

UX/UI Designer

2017 - 2017

The Cambridge Project - UCSD

Created low-fidelity mockups of an app that was intended to guide people with mental disabilities through exercises assigned by their doctors and track their progress on a weekly basis. With a team of five students at UCSD and three students from Cambridge, we created a branding scheme and multiple wireframes through the process of iterative design.

EDUCATION

University of California, San Diego

2014 - 2018

Senior studying Cognitive Science with a Specialization in Human-Computer Interaction and a minor in Design.

PROFICIENCIES

- Well versed in Adobe Creative Cloud programs including Photoshop, InDesign, Lightroom, Premiere Pro, Experience Design, and Illustrator.
- Working knowledge of Microsoft Office applications such as Word, Powerpoint, and Excel.
- Experience collaborating with others using Google Drive, Slides, and Docs.
- Basic knowledge of computer programming languages such as HTML, CSS, and Java.